cars24.com 2019-07-07

# CARS24 | Privacy Policy

CARS24 Services Private Ltd. (“ **CARS24** ” or the “ **Company** ”) firmly believes in the highest standards of integrity in relation to information provided by its customers at the time of interaction with the Company, and otherwise. 

## 1\. General

CARS24 values your privacy and commits to protect information disclosed by the users (“ **You** ”) to CARS24 either by means of the CARS24 website/mobile application. Please read the following policy (hereinafter referred to as " **Privacy Policy** ") to understand practices of CARS24, and specifically with regards, as to how CARS24 treats information disclosed by You. By using the domain and sub-domains of www.cars24.com including its mobile applications (hereinafter referred to as “ **CARS24 Website** ”). You agree that You have acceded to the terms of the present Privacy Policy. In the event that You do not wish to be bound by these terms, You have a choice, which is (naturally and obviously) free from any form of coercion or undue influence, to not access the CARS24 Website. This Privacy Policy also applies generally to our parent, affiliates, subsidiaries, or joint venture websites. 

## 2\. Your Consent

We request You to carefully read this Privacy Policy and Terms of Use under the different tab before sharing personal information with us. By browsing, visiting, accessing and/or using the services on CARS24 Website (or searching for any of the pages on CARS24 Website), You explicitly consents and agrees to our Privacy Policy laid out herein. You also agree that the information furnished by You is lawful, true and correct and does not violate or infringe any laws. No liability pertaining to the authenticity/ genuineness/ misrepresentation/ fraud/ negligence, etc. of the information disclosed shall lie on the Company nor will the Company in any way be responsible to verify any information obtained from You. 

## 3\. Information

This Privacy Policy applies to information that: 

### 3.1. Personal Information:

Users of CARS24 may voluntarily while registering/interacting on CARS24 Website, provide personal information viz. email address, name, phone number, etc.; and 

### 3.2. Non- Personal Information:

Information, (viz. type of internet browser and operating system used, domain name of the website from which You came, number of visits, average time spent on the site, pages viewed etc.) may be picked up automatically and without explicitly being provided by You, but during your interaction with the CARS24 Website by use of certain technologies, such as Cookies and Web Beacons. 

## 4\. Types of information received by CARS24

The following type of information about You may be collected and processed by the Company: 

  * Information about your internet connection and mobile device
  * The equipment used by You to browse the CARS24 Website
  * Your usage details in respect of the CARS24 Website
  * Internet Protocol (IP) details/ address
  * Your current location
  * Computer operating system
  * Preferences and settings such as time zone and language
  * Account / User Information – including but not limited to your name, address, email address, mobile / telephone number, gender, income, and any other information sought by CARS24 at the time of your making an account with CARS24, or obtaining a quote from CARS24
  * Your searches, the results You selected from the search and other activities
  * Your browsing information (browsing length, details of online ads that You clicked on)
  * Your transactional information
  * Details in respect of your vehicle, including but not limited to make, model, identification details of the vehicle, prior use, history, insurance details, registration certificate details, etc.

Please note that the following list is only illustrative, and is by no means, exhaustive. Kindly note that any user-generated content such as reviews, blogs, testimonials etc. shall be treated by CARS24 as its own. 

## 5\. Third Party Interaction

You may access the CARS24 Website through third-party websites over which CARS24 has no control. You may optionally provide CARS24 with information through third-party sign-in services such as Facebook, Pinterest, Twitter, Instagram, and Google Plus. In such cases, CARS24 fetches and stores whatever information is made available to CARS24 by You through these sign-in services. Please also note that CARS24 reserves its rights to use information provided by You, in consonance with all relevant laws and guidelines. 

Further, it is clarified that while Your usage of CARS24 Website, You might see the links to the third party website / advertisements / electronic communication service, which are provided by the third parties. As the operation of the third party is not under control of the Company, therefore the Company does not make any endorsement / guarantee of any service or product offered through third party websites nor make any representation related to the any privacy policy or other policies of such third party. Any usage of such third-party website or availing any service or product through third party shall be at Your risk and the Company is not responsible for any loss / damage or otherwise. It is recommended that You should review the privacy policy of such third-party websites prior to using such websites. 

## 6\. How your information helps in providing You with a more optimized interface and experience

CARS24 uses the information that You provide to enhance the functionality and improve the quality of your interaction with CARS24 and to personalize your experience while using the CARS24 services. 

## 7\. Public Posts

As part of CARS24 services, You may provide your reviews, feedback, comments, ratings, photos, etc. on the public groups (Posts). The Company retains an unconditional right to remove and delete any Post or such part of the Post that, in the opinion of the Company, is false, malafide and misrepresenting. All Posts shall be publicly accessible and visible to all users and therefore, You should be careful about revealing any sensitive details about yourself in such Posts. The Company reserves the right to use and reproduce your Posts for any purpose. Further, the Company may share your Posts with the service providers, businesses or any other third party. If You delete your Posts from any of the public groups, copies of such Posts may remain viewable in archived pages, or such Posts may have been copied or stored by any other user(s) of that public group. 

## 8\. Opting Out

You may opt out of receiving promotional emails from the Company by following the instructions in those emails. If You opt out, the Company may still send You non-promotional emails, such as emails about your account. 

**Cookie choices:**  Most web browsers are set to accept cookies by default. If You prefer, You can usually choose to set your browser to remove cookies and to reject cookies. If You choose to remove cookies or reject cookies, this could affect certain features of the CARS24 Website. 

## 9\. How CARS24 uses and shares the information collected

CARS24 uses information collected from and about You for a variety of purposes, including (but not limited) to: 

  * Processing and responding to your queries
  * Protect and improve the services that CARS24 offer
  * Understanding users (what they do on our services, what features they like, how they use them, etc.), improving content and features of CARS24 services (such as by personalizing content to your interests), processing and completing your transactions, and making special offers
  * Administering services and diagnosing technical problems
  * Sending You communications that You have requested or that may be of interest to You
  * Sending You questions that You may be able to answer if You have registered with CARS24, or have scheduled an appointment at a CARS24 location or branch
  * Sending You information about your vehicle pursuant to your visit to a CARS24 branch or location
  * Enabling and filtering advertisements that are relevant to You
  * Generating and reviewing reports and data about, and to conduct research on, CARS24 user base and service usage patterns
  * Administering contests and sweepstakes
  * Providing You with customer support
  * Providing You with notices about your account
  * Internal purposes such as auditing, data analysis and research relating to Company’s services on CARS24 Website
  * Carrying out CARS24 obligations and enforcing rights arising from any contracts entered into between You and CARS24, including for billing and collection
  * Carrying out CARS24 obligations that arise out all relevant statute in relation to your vehicle, and in relation to your transaction and interaction with CARS24
  * Allowing You to participate in interactive features offered by CARS24
  * Granting You opportunities to avail special offers/vouchers being offered by third parties by You being a customer of CARS24 and/or showing your interest for the services of CARS24
  * CARS24 is allowed to share the information, which You have shared on our CARS24 Website, with our alliance partners. These alliances/ partnerships are done to provide perks and convenience to You. By clicking on the submit button, the Company and the partner will consider You an interested user and will use the details submitted by You to contact You and give You a customized experience of our services.

CARS24 may use the information collected from You to enable CARS24 to display advertisements to its advertisers’ target audiences. Even though CARS24 does not disclose your personal information for these purposes without your consent, if You click on, or otherwise interact with an advertisement, the advertiser may assume that You meet its target criteria. 

## 10\. Disclosure to third parties

CARS24 shall be at liberty to disclose your information or part thereof to third party service providers who may facilitate the providing of services, on our behalf. These service providers have access to your data only to perform the tasks as stipulated by CARS24 and are obligated not to disclose or use it for any other purpose. CARS24 may also share personal information with third-party vendors, consultants, and other service providers who work for the Company, who are bound by contractual obligations to keep personal information confidential and use it only for the purposes for which the Company disclose it to them. 

## 11\. Amendment

The Company reserves the right to amend or modify this Privacy Policy at any time, as and when the need arises. We request you to regularly check this Privacy Policy from time to time to keep you updated about changes made. Your continued use of the services provided by CARS24 after any changes, shall be deemed to be your acceptance of such changes. 

## 12\. Contact Us

In the event You have any complaints or concerns with respect to the CARS24 Website or our services or if You have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please feel free to contact us on 1800 258 5656 (between 8 am - 9 pm) or reach out to our customer support at [care@cars24.com](mailto:care@cars24.com). 

## 13\. Grievance Redressal

In compliance with Information Technology Act, 2000 and the rules made thereunder, the Grievance Officer of CARS24 for the purpose of this Agreement shall be: 

  * **Grievance Officer Name:**  Ms. Ashita Sharma
  * **Email Address:** [grievanceofficer@cars24.com](mailto:grievanceofficer@cars24.com)

_(Please include the following subject line in the email – “Attention: Grievance Officer”)_
